Inventory of the United States. Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service miscellaneous records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound Recordings, 1941-1946
  - American correspondent reports, 1941-1946
    - Jack Mahon radio report on the Japanese fleet, 1945 March 21 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 316: Mahon reports that the American forces have found the Japanese fleet and are now attacking it.
    - Jack Mahon radio report on the death of Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1945 April (Record cabinet)
      Mahon reports from Guam about the reaction to the death of President Franklin D. Roosevelt. He concentrates on the reaction of journalists to the news.
    - Jack Mahon radio report, number 752, and test cuts, 1945 September 17 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Mahon reports from Tokyo about the occupation of Japan and reduction in American troop levels. Included is how the Japanese government will be used to prevent social disintegration.
      Part 2: Test cuts.
      The disc hole of the source disc is not directly in the center, thus the sound quality is poor.
    - Jack Mahon radio reports, circa 1945 June 21-22 (Record cabinet)
      In the first report, Mahon reports on the casualties in the Pacific Theater of World War II. While he mentions casualties on both sides, he concentrates on the amount of deceased Japanese soldiers.
      In the second and third reports, Mahon talks about the battle of Okinawa.
    - Jack Mahon radio reports, 1945 August 16 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 679: In the first recording on this disc, Mahon sends an administrative note from Paul Manning. In the second, he reports on Japanese officials' actions following the end of the war.
    - Jack Mahon, Vice Admiral Richmond Kelly Turner, and General Holland Smith radio broadcasts, 1941-1945 (Record cabinet)
      On side A of this disc, Mahon describes the efforts of the American military to find the Japanese forces during World War II. From the tone of the report, it likely comes from early in the war.
      Side B consists of an introduction to two military officials' commentary, Vice Admiral Richmond Kelly Turner and General Holland Smith.
    - Joe Hainline and Robert McCormick radio reports, 1945-1946 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, Joe Hainline interviews Jay Finley of Palo Alto, California about being shot down and spending five days on a life raft.
      IN the second cut, Robert McCormick and Joe Hainline reflect on the death of Ernie Pyle.
    - John Cooper radio report, 1945 November 12 (Record cabinet)
      Cooper delivers the inaugural radio report from the Pacific with the assistance of the U.S. Navy.
    - John Thorton voice letter home and Royal Arch Gunnison radio report, 194? November 22 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Thorton discusses his life and work in San Francisco to his family back in New York.
      Part 2: Gunnison reports from the Philippines on Japanese radio propaganda. This is another copy of the program heard on 58011_a_0009528.
    - Ken MacLaughlin and Charles Minor radio reports, 1945 August 27-29 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, on 27 August 1945, Ken MacLaughlin reports on the reunification of China following the defeat of Japan. He discusses a meeting between Chiang Kai-Shek and Mao Zedong. He presents the meeting as the only chance to prevent a Chinese civil war.
      In the second cut, Charles Minor reports from Manila about the new Sino-Russian agreement and the possibility of a Chinese civil war.
      The third cut, from 29 August 1945, Ken MacLaughlin reports on General Wainwright and meeting between Chiang Kai-Shek and Mao Zedong.
    - Larry Tighe and Jack Mahon radio reports, 1945 April 27 (Record cabinet)
      Larry Tighe(?) and Jack Mahon individually report from Guam on Japanese military tactics that are very similar to German tactics.
    - Larry Tye radio report from Guam, 1945 February 24 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 250: Tye describes the typical experience of the American soldier in the Pacific Theater. He places the listener in the shoes of a GI, narrating in the second voice.
    - Leslie Nichols and Bud Foster radio reports, 1945 April 1 (Record cabinet)
      Nichols reports from Okinawa and Foster reports from Iwo Jima on American forces in Japan.
    - Leslie Nichols and Don Pryor radio reports, 1945 April 18 (Record cabinet)
      Nichols and Pryor separately report from Okinawa about the death of fellow journalist Ernie Pyle.
    - Leslie Nichols interviews Vice Admiral John Sidney McCain, 1944 November 28 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 82
      On side A, Nichols features the work of Vice Admiral John Sidney McCain.
      Side B is the 21 October episode of "The Radio Workshop," a Halloween-themed program geared towards children.
    - Leslie Nichols radio broadcast concerning the battle of the Philippines, 1945 April 14 (Record cabinet)
      Nichols discusses naval battle for the Philippines, including the contributions of FDR and Admiral McCain to this effort.
    - Leslie Nichols radio report, 1945 April 1 (Record cabinet)
      Nichols describes Okinawa following the American invasion.
    - Leslie Nichols radio report, 1945 April 13 (Record cabinet)
      Nichols describes how one battalion learned of the death of President Roosevelt amidst active fighting on Okinawa.
    - Leslie Nichols radio report, 1944 December 7 (Record cabinet)
      106
      103
      Job #103 Guam - Leslie Nichols's for MBS
      DEC. 7-44
      Heavy QRM
    - Leslie Nichols radio reports, 1944 December 5-6 (Record cabinet)
      These recordings are finished broadcasts.
      In both, an anchor in America introduces correspondent Leslie Nichols, reporting from Guam. He talks about naval battles in the Philippine Sea. In the report from 6 December 1944, he focuses on Navy pilot Speedball Harris.
    - Leslie Nichols reports on the death of Ernie Pyle, 1945 April 18 (Record cabinet)
      Nichols reports from Okinawa on the death of journalist Ernie Pyle. He includes how the soldiers viewed Pyle.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System broadcast, 1945 April 19 (Record cabinet)
      Jack Mahon and Tim Lemmert report on the American advances against the Japanese.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System broadcast of Operation Crossroads, 1946 June 30 (Record cabinet)
      The Mutual Broadcasting System covers the Able atomic bomb test just off Bikini Lagoon. It was the first drop against simulated naval forces, and the fourth atomic bomb ever exploded, following the original test and the two dropped on Japan. The anchor emphasizes this is a military and scientific exercise to better understand atomic power. Don Bell reports from the scene. Bombadier Harold H. Wood speaks.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System broadcast recordings, 1944 November 3 (Record cabinet)
      The recording on side A is Leslie Nichols providing a live description of an air battle.
      The recording on side B is a program dedicated to all the American soldiers. It concerns the girlfriends of soldiers fighting abroad and how they might write to their beaus.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System news roundup concerning the Pacific Theater of World War II, 1945 March 30 (Record cabinet)
      Includes Jack Mahon reporting about the Red Cross and Arthur Primm interviewing survivors of the Bismarck Sea.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System news roundup, number 597, 1945 July 3 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: Mutual Broadcasting System news roundup, number 597.
      Part 2: The words of Joseph Stilwell.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio broadcast concerning Japan's offer of surrender, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      Charles Minor in Chungking, Paul Manning in Guam, and Don Bell in Manila report on Japan's offer to surrender in World War II. Manning speaks about the offer. Bell speaks about the soldiers' reaction. The anchor says the President has yet to receive an official offer of surrender, and that fighting will continue as is until one is received.
      The disc also includes a report about the effect the end of the war will have on Hawaii.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio broadcast covering VJ day, 1945 August 14 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 670
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio broadcast, 1945 August 7 (Record cabinet)
      Side A is a muffled audio report.
      Side B is Don Bell in Manila and Paul Manning in Guam interviewing soldiers for their stories. Also, Charles Minor reports from Chungking about the Chinese response to the atomic bomb.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio broadcast recording, 1945 August 14 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 670: This recording is a finished news program from the Mutual Broadcasting System. The news concerns the Pacific Theater of World War II. An anchor in America cuts to three correspondents in the Pacific. Don Bell reports from the Philippines about the coming peace in the Pacific. Owen Cunningham reports from Hawaii about Americans of Japanese descent. Paul Manning reports from Guam about the rumors of a peace agreement.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio broadcasts concerning the American invasion of Japan, 1945 August 29 (Record cabinet)
      Jack Mahon reports on the invasion of Japan and the release of prisoners-of-war.
      Frederick Opper reports from the Japan suburbs.
      Bob Brumby reports about the interaction of American and Japanese soldiers.
      Bob Brumby and another reporter recall interviews with American soldiers concerning what the Japanese think of the American occupation as well as what the Americans think of the occupation.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio broadcasts, 1945 September 7 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 737
      On side A is a program, produced in San Francisco, about the American occupation of Japan. It includes coverage of the first American flag raising over Tokyo.
      On side B are three cuts. In the first, Jack Mahon makes his first report from Radio Tokyo. The second is an outtake of a news roundup. The third cut is an interview with three young women from the Bay Area.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio broadcasts, 1945 January 7-December 14 (Record cabinet)
      The first cut on side A is a clothing drive held by WOR.
      Robert Stewart reports from Manila on 12 December 1945 on crime in the city.
      The last cut on side A is a report from Fort Mason, San Francisco, on what American soldiers returning from Asia are buying for their families for Christmas.
      The first cut on side B is Robert Stewart reporting from Manila about a hanging.
      The second cut on side B is Don Bell reporting from Manila on a meeting by 25,000 GIs on "the SNAFUing of the demobilization program."
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio broadcasts, 1945 December 21 (Record cabinet)
      Side A is coverage of the change of command for the United States Pacific fleet.
      Side B is Robert Stewart reporting about Filipino-US relations, especially regarding the trial and execution of Yamashita.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio coverage of the return of army nurses at Hamilton Beach, California, 1945 February 24 (Record cabinet)
      Part 1: An MBS journalist attempts to interview army nurses returning from Balan.
      Part 2: The journalist interviews Major Juanita Redman, who was in charge of getting the 54 nurses home from the Pacific.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio coverage of the second atomic bomb test at Bikini, 1946 July 24 (Record cabinet)
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio news broadcasts, 1945 November 14-15 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 779: These broadcasts contain most of a broadcast program on the plight of an American-born citizen accused of being a German alien by the military on Honolulu.
      There is also a report by Bell on Japanese occupation and reparation payments.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio news program, 1945 April 2 (Record cabinet)
      This program features Joe Hainline, Don Pryor, and Jack Mahon reporting from Guam, Okinawa, and Iwo Jima.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio program 355, 1945 April 2 (Record cabinet)
      A news roundup of activity in the Pacific Theater of WWII. Correspondents include Leslie Nichols, Don Pryor, and Bud Foster.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio program, 1945 April 1 (Record cabinet)
      This program is an update on the Pacific Theater of World War II. Jack Mahon reports from Guam, Leslie Nichols reports from Okinawa, and Bob Brumby reports from Chungking.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio program, 1945 April 18 (Record cabinet)
      Jack Mahon offers from Guam an update on various events in the Pacific Theater of World War II.
      Leslie Nichols reports from Okinawa on the death of Ernie Pyle on Ie Shima.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio program on the sixth plenary session of the United Nations Conference on International Organization, 1945 May 1 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 498: Features a summary, commentary, and sound clips from the proceedings. Much of the program is a debate by MBS staff on the admittance of Argentina.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio report from the Pacific, 1945 April 21 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 459/460: This is the Mutual Broadcasting System's weekly Pacific news roundup. Correspondents are Jack Mahon, Leslie Nichols, and Arthur Gates. In addition to the news of the war effort, one segment concerns Gates discussing the United Nations Conference on International Organization in San Francisco.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 July 13 (Record cabinet)
      A: Christian Science Monitor reporter Gordon Walker reports from Guam on an American attack on Hokkaido.
      B: Jack Mahon reports from a battleship on the attack on Hokkaido, comparing it to Tokyo.
      C: Christian Science Monitor Gordon Walker reports from Guam on the attack on Tokyo.
      D: Concerns heavy bombardment of Japan by America.
      E: Describes an American attack on the main island of Japan.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 June 14 (Record cabinet)
      In the first recording, Leslie Nichols reports from Guam, introducing Lt. Dale Evans who recalls a mission gone wrong.
      In the second and third recordings, Don Bell and Cedric Foster, respectively, report from Manila on the devastation felt by the Philippines.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 August 26-27 (Record cabinet)
      Mutual Broadcasting System correspondents Joe Henleim, Jack Mahon, Bob Brumby, and Paul Manning offer reports of American activity on mainland Japan and Guam.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 August 27 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 706: Norman Paige and Jack Mahon report from the Pacific.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 August 28 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, Bob Brumby reports from Okinawa on the ease of occupying Japan, concentrating on the state of the infrastructure.
      In the second, Brumby talks about Col. Lackey and the first landing in Japan.
      In the third cut, Edwards interviews a Japanese lieutenant commander.
      In the fourth, Jack Mahon comments on health care of the soldiers.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 April 29 (Record cabinet)
      Tim Lemmert reports from Okinawa on the fighting in the Pacific Theater.
      Jack Mahon reports from Guam on the false news that the European war was over and the status of the Pacific Theater.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 August 29 (Record cabinet)
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 August 29-30 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 712: On side A, Jack Mahon reports following a press conference held by Admiral Nimitz concerning the coming occupation of Japan.
      On side B, Tim McLaughlin reports from Chungking about Lt. Gen. Wainwright. He then speaks about Mao Zedong being in Chungking at the same time and his coming meeting with Chiang Kai-Shek.
      Also on side B, Bob Brumby reports. The audio quality is poor, but sounds like it is about General MacArthur and the occupation of Japan.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 June 6-8 (Record cabinet)
      Jack Mahon reports from Okinawa and concentrates on how the military is supplying the armed forces.
      Leslie reports from Guam on the bombing of Osaka.
      American Red Cross reporter Susan Tate reports from Manila on eating with soldiers.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 December (Record cabinet)
      Disc 773: Don Bell reports from Tokyo on a person that immigrated to the US from Japan before renouncing American citizenship and returning to Japan. He also talks about children receiving their last meal.
      Another story is about Christmas at the Waldorf-Astoria. Arthur Prinn then describes Christmas in Toil Land, reporting from San Francisco.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1944 November 28-29 (Record cabinet)
      On the first side, Leslie Nichols reports on Vice Admiral John McCain.
      On the second side, R.A. Gunnison reports on the "improving" condition of the Pacific Theater in World War II.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports from Okinawa, 194? April 30 (Record cabinet)
      Norman Paige and another correspondent report from Okinawa.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 November 13 (Record cabinet)
      On side A, Don Bell reports from Tokyo on the disarmament of Japan by the Allies. He says the process will take much longer than expected. He also provides a brief survey of Japan's experimental military technology, which he concludes was far behind that of America.
      On side B, Arthur Gaeth reports on the soon-to-come Nuremberg trials.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports from the Pacific, 1944 December 15-16 (Record cabinet)
      In the recording on side A, Gunnison describes the American advance towards Manila.
      The recording on side B is a produced broadcast featuring an anchor that cuts to correspondents Gunnison and Paige reporting from the Pacific.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports from the Pacific, 1945 May 6-June 5 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 558: The broadcast topics include: American advances on Okinawa, Japanese plane technology, military bases on Okinawa, and an interview with two soldiers that fought in both Normandy and Iwo Jima.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, 1945 June 6 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 559: On side A of this recording, Leslie Nichols reports from Guam on the anniversary of the Normandy landing. He introduced Marine Corps Sergeant Bill Roth who interviews two soldiers that were at both D-Day and the battle of Iwo Jima. The soldiers offer their comparisons of the German and Japanese soldiers.
      On side B, Don Bell gives an overview of the American effort in the Pacific.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio reports, number 820, 1946 June 29 (Record cabinet)
      These reports concern the first atomic bomb test of Operation Crossroads at Bikini Atoll.
      Part 1: Short clip on the evacuation of people in preparation for the test.
      Part 2: W. W. Chaplin reporting from the Army radio ship Stimuli at Kwajalein five-and-a-half hours before the first test. He analyzes the work done to ensure there are not "mishaps" with the test, focusing on the relocation of the native people to Ebeye.
      Part 3: W. W. Chaplin reports from Kwajalein as Dave's Dream, the plane carrying the bomb, leaves for Bikini and discusses its crew and course.
      Part 4: Don Bell reports from the U.S.S. Mt. McKinley at Bikini the day before the Able test. He relays the thoughts of Admirals William H.P. Blandy and William "Deak" Parsons on the weather conditions for the test.
      Part 5: A recording with poor audio quality of John Mosley's aerial view of the explosion.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio special report on the death of Adolf Hitler, 1945 May 1 (Record cabinet)
      Various overseas correspondents report on reactions of the 1st, 7th, and 9th armies to unconfirmed news of Adolf Hitler's death.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio transmissions, 1945 (Record cabinet)
      On side A, a reporter for the American Red Cross, Doug Disbrow (sp?), interviews American soldiers in the Pacific Theater of World War II, as well as an Australian reporter. From the content of the interviews--the soldiers mention occupation forces--they probably occurred towards the end or after the war.
      On side B are a variety of radio transmissions. The first is a report by Jack Mahon from Tokyo on the reduction of occupation forces in Japan. The second and third recordings describe a British-American heavyweight boxing match. The fourth and fifth concern the military implications of cosmic rays.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio transmissions, 1945 July 14 (Record cabinet)
      In the first cut, Gordon Walker reports from Guam about the American bombing of the Japanese home islands.
      The second is a communiqué from Admiral Nimitz, number 428. It concerns the American bombing of Hokkaido.
      In the third cut, Gordon Walker reports about the American attack on Hokkaido.
      The fourth cut is unintelligible.
      In the fifth cut, Jack Mahon also reports on the attack on Hokkaido.
    - Mutual Broadcasting System radio transmissions, 194? December (Record cabinet)
      The recording on side A is two people discussing possible broadcasts related to Christmas, especially one by Nichols. One speaker, John Hooley, sounds like he was recorded via radio transmissions and the other, also named John, in the studio.
      The recording on side B is R. A. Gunnison reporting from the Philippines on the campaign of General MacArthur.
    - National Broadcasting Company report about the atomic bomb test at Bikini Lagoon, 1946 July 25 (Record cabinet)
      Various reporters contribute to a program from Bikini Lagoon about the Baker atomic bomb test. They describe the area immediately before, the extent of the explosion, and immediately after the underwater explosion. The explosion occurs at 5:11 into the program, with Admiral Blandy immediately confirming the successful explosion.
      Don Mosley, Clete Roberts, Don Bell, and Ralph Howard Peterson report from the USS Mt. McKinley. Another journalist views the explosion from a B29 in the air.
      See 58011_a_0011198 for another copy of this program.
    - Norman Page and Bud Foster radio reports, 1945 April 7 (Record cabinet)
      Disc 388
      Cut 1: Norman Page reports from Okinawa on the American advances on the Japanese Navy.
      Cut 2: Bud Foster reports from Okinawa on April 7, 1945 about the Japanese air forces.
    - Norman Page and Jack Hooley radio reports, 1945 April 18 (Record cabinet)
      Three cuts are on the original disc.
      Part 1: Norman Page partial recording.
      Part 2: Jack Hooley
      Part 3: Jack Hooley
    - Norman Page and Jack Mahon radio reports, 1945 April 7 (Record cabinet)
      Three cuts/parts are on the original disc.
      Part 1: Administrative transmission.
      Part 2: Norman Page speaks from Okinawa, having just returned from the forward lines with the 24th Army corps. Beyond the fighting, he reports about Okinawan refugees.
      Sound quality is less than ideal due to poor reception.
      Part 3: Jack Mahon
    - Norman Page and Jack Mahon radio reports, 1945 April 5 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 373
      Part 1: Norman Page reports from Okinawa.
      Part 2: Jack Mahon interviews Captain T. J. Heading.
    - Norman Page and Joe Henline radio broadcasts, 1945 April 18-19 (Record cabinet)
    - Norman Page radio report about his travels with the Marines, 1945 April 2 (Record cabinet)
      Recording 349
    - Norman Page radio report, 1945 April 1 (Record cabinet)
      Page reports from Okinawa.
    - Norman Page radio report, 1945 April 19 (Record cabinet)
      #450